<regtext version="2.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="regtext.xsd"><text_id><id_key><state>ID</state><number>10865</number></id_key><version>Adopted Pending Rule</version><version_date>00000000</version_date><version_sequence>0</version_sequence></text_id><transmission_info><process_date>20211206</process_date></transmission_info><document><head><p class="indent"><b>December 1, 2021 &#x2013; Vol. 21-12</b></p><p class="center"><b>IDAPA 20 &#x2013; IDAHO DEPARTMENT OF LANDS</b></p><p class="indent"><b>20.06.01 &#x2013; RULES OF THE IDAHO BOARD OF SCALING PRACTICES DOCKET NO. 20-0601-2101 (NEW CHAPTER)</b></p><p class="indent"><b>NOTICE OF RULEMAKING &#x2013; ADOPTION OF PENDING FEE RULE</b></p></head><digest><p class="indent"><b>EFFECTIVE DATE:</b> This rule has been adopted by the Idaho Board of Scaling Practices and is now pending review by the 2022 Idaho State Legislature for final approval. Pursuant to Section 67-5224(5)(c), Idaho Code, this pending rule will not become final and effective until it has been approved by concurrent resolution of the legislature because of the fee being imposed through this rulemaking. The pending fee rule becomes final and effective upon adoption of the concurrent resolution or upon the date specified in the concurrent resolution unless the rule is rejected. <b>AUTHORITY:</b> In compliance with Section 67-5224, Idaho Code, notice is hereby given that this agency has adopted a pending fee rule. The action is authorized pursuant to Sections 38-1208 and 38-1220, Idaho Code. <b>DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY:</b> The following is a concise explanatory st atement of the reasons for adopting the pending fee rule and a statement of any change between the text of the proposed rule and the text of the pending fee rule with an explanation of the reasons for the change:</p><table><tr><td><p class="indent">The Idaho Board </p></td><td><p class="indent">of Scaling Practices is adopting a newcubic log scaling manual to give another option as to how logs are scaled and to maintain a consistent cubic scale volume anywhere within the state should parties elect to scale in cubic volume. By incorporating by reference the&#x201c;Idaho Cubic Log Scaling Manual,&#x201d; this pending rule will ensure that both Scribner and cubic s Board of Scaling Practices. The new cubic manual is an alternative to the current &#x201c;Idaho Log Scaling Manual&#x201d; and is not meant as a replacement.</p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="indent">Following Executive </p></td><td><p class="indent">Order 2020-01, Zero-Based Regulation,this rule chapter is scheduled to be repealed and replaced in 2021 for review during the 2022 legislative session. The pending rule has words and restrictions removed, wherever possible, to decrease the total word count and reduce the overall regulatory burden.</p></td></tr><tr><td>There are no chang</td><td>es to the pending fee rule and it is being adopted as originally proposed. The complete text of the proposed rule was published in the September 1, 2021, Idaho Administrative Bulletin, <del></del></td></tr><tr><td>>Vol. 21-9, pages 98-107<del></del> The &#x201c;Idaho Cubic Log Scaling Manual&#x201d; and an unofficial strikethrough version of the proposed rule, which shows changes made through this rulemaking, are available on the Idaho Department of Lands website at the following web address: <del><td> </td></del></td></tr><tr><td>>https://www.idl.idaho.gov/rulemaking/docket-20-0601-2101<del></del>.</td><td> </td></tr></table><p class="indent"><b>FEE SUMMARY:</b></p><p class="indent">The following are the previously approved and odified fees that have not changed: <b>scaling</b> assessment fee paid to a dedicated scaling account for ll <b>scaled</b> timber harvested within the state of Idaho; administrative fees for registration, renewal, and transferof log brands; fees for testing and issuance of a temporary scaling permit, specialty scaling license, and standard scaling license; fee to renew a specialty or standard scaling license; and fee for a requested check scale involving a scaling dispute. These fees are being imposed pursuant to Section 38-1209, Idaho Code. This rulemaking does not change any of the fees imposed.</p><fiscal_note><p class="indent"><b>FISCAL IMPACT:</b> The following is a specific description, if applicable, of any negative fiscal impact on the state general fund greater than ten thousand dollars ($10,000) during the fiscal year: These rules will have no impact on the state general fund.</p></fiscal_note><p class="indent"><b>ASSISTANCE ON TECHNICAL QUESTIONS:</b> For assistance on technical questions concerning this pending fee rule, contact Shawn Inman at (208) 769-1445.</p><p class="indent">DATED this 29th day of October, 2021.</p><p class="indent">Shawn Inman, Executive Director</p><p class="indent">Phone: (208) 769-1445</p><p class="indent">Idaho Board of Scaling Practices</p><p class="indent">Fax: (208) 769-1524</p><p class="indent">3284 W Industrial Loop</p><p class="indent"> <del>stibsp@ibsp.idaho.gov</del> </p><p class="indent">Coeur d&#x2019;Alene, ID 83815</p></digest></document></regtext>