<regtext version="2.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="regtext.xsd">
<sni>ea6c7ade8e21baf12c95d5900097439d</sni>
<text_id>
<id_key>
<state>MS</state>
<number>17100</number>
</id_key>
<version>Adopted Rule</version>
<version_date>00000000</version_date>
<version_sequence>0</version_sequence>
</text_id>
<transmission_info>
<process_date>20221018</process_date>
</transmission_info>
<document>
<digest>
<attach file="ms_17100_a_attach1.jpg" title="Notice"></attach>
<attach file="ms_17100_a_attach2.jpg" title="Resolution"></attach>
</digest>
<text>
<p class="indent"><b>Title 30: Professions and Occupations </b> </p>
<p class="indent"><b>Part 1903: RULES AND REGULATIONS FOR MARRIAGE AND FAMILY THERAPISTS </b> </p>
<p class="indent"><b>Part1903 Chapter 1: General Provisions</b> </p>
<p class="indent">Rule 1.1 GENERAL </p>
<p class="indent">A. The rules and regulations pertaining to marriage and family therapists include all items in Parts 1901 and 1903 of these rules and regulations. </p>
<p class="indent">B. The Board may revise the rules and regulations from time to time as the Board deems necessary. </p>
<p class="indent">C. Once new or revised rules and regulations are adopted by the Board, the Board and all applicants and licensees must operate under the new rules and regulations. However, persons with completed applications for licensure on file at the time new rules and regulations are adopted by the Board, will be licensed under the rules in effect on the date their completed application was received by the Board. </p>
<p class="indent">Source: Miss. Code Ann. &#xa7;&#xa7;73-53-11(1) (c) and (k), 73-54-3 and 73-54-11(1) (2008 &amp; Supp. 2011). </p>
<p class="indent">Rule 1.2 DEFINITIONS </p>
<p class="indent">As used in these Rules and Regulations and in the Mississippi Marriage and Family Therapy Act of 1997, the following words and terms shall have the meaning ascribed herein below: </p>
<p class="indent">A. "Act" is the Mississippi <i>Marriage and Family Therapy Licensure Act of 1997, </i>Title 73, Chapter 54 of the Mississippi Code of 1972, as amended. </p>
<p class="indent">B. "Advertise" means, but is not limited to, issuing or causing to be distributed any card, sign or device to any person; causing, permitting or allowing any sign or marking on or in any building; broadcasting by radio or television; or advertising on the internet or by any other means designed to secure public attention. </p>
<p class="indent">C. "AAMFT" means the American Association for Marriage and Family Therapy. </p>
<p class="indent">D. "Client contact hours" means both direct client contact hours as defined below and administrative and supportive client associated hours as defined by the individual accredited Institute of Higher Learning. </p>
<p class="indent">E. Clinical Supervision" means the direct clinical review, for the purposes of training or teaching by a supervisor, of the supervisee's interaction with a client. </p>
<p class="indent">F. "COAMFTE" means the Commission on Accreditation for Marriage and Family Therapy Education. </p>
<p class="indent">G. "Code of Ethics" means the current Code of Ethics of the American Association for Marriage and Family Therapy. </p>
<p class="indent">H. "Completed Application" means the official marriage and family therapy application prescribed by the Board with the signature of the applicant, fees and all supporting information and documents requested by the Board. </p>
<p class="indent">I. "Contact Hour" means one 60-minute clock hour of an approved educational activity offered by an approved provider with no less than 50 minutes of instructional content within the 60 minutes. </p>
<p class="indent">J. "Consultation" or "Conferring" means a professional collaborative relationship between a licensed marriage and family therapist and a qualified licensed individual or other professional of relative equal expertise or status in which the other licensed individual or professional makes an assessment based on information supplied by the licensed marriage and family therapist and jointly develops a written treatment plan with the licensed marriage and family therapist which indicates the responsibility of each professional for implementing elements of the plan, updating the plan, and assessing the client's progress. </p>
<p class="indent">K. "Continuing Education" means programs and/or activities designed to and have the content intended to enhance the general or specialized marriage and family therapy practice, knowledge. The primary objective of continuing education must be to maintain and improve the quality of professional services in marriage and family therapy provided to the public; maintain and improve the therapist's knowledge of current research, techniques, and practice; and provide other resources which will improve skill and competence in marriage and family therapy. values, skills, ethics and/or </p>
<p class="indent">L. "Direct Client Contact" means face-to-face interaction, either in-person or through a secure video conferencing platform between the therapist and an individual, couple, or family. </p>
<p class="indent">M. "Direct Clinical Review" means board approved supervision that consists of case related interactive face to face, either in-person or through a secure video conferencing platform meeting between the supervisor and supervisee. </p>
<p class="indent">N. "Examination" means the test or exam endorsed or prescribed by the Association for Marital and Family Therapy Regulatory Boards. </p>
<p class="indent">O. Face-to-Face Supervision" means supervision conducted by a supervisor, either in- person or through a secure video conferencing platform,of the person being supervised for the purpose of carrying out the supervision functions described in Part 1903, Chapter 2, Rule 2.2 (C)(3)( i). </p>
<p class="indent">P. "Good Moral Character" shall have the meaning set forth in Part 1901, Chapter 2, Rule 2.1 of these Rules and Regulations. </p>
<p class="indent">Q. "Group Supervision" means a minimum of three (3) and no more than eight (8) marriage and family supervisees or associates in a clinical setting during the supervision hour. A supervision hour is fifty (50) minutes. </p>
<p class="indent">R. "Individual Supervision" shall mean a maximum of two (2) marriage and family supervisees or associates in a clinical setting during the supervision hour. A supervision hour is fifty (50) minutes. </p>
<p class="indent">S. "Institution of Higher Education" means any college or university which is accredited by a regional accrediting body recognized by the United States Department of Education or a substantially equivalent foreign institution. </p>
<p class="indent">T. "Licensed Marriage and Family Therapist (LMFT)" means a person to whom a license has been issued under the Mississippi Code of 1972 as amended, Section 73-53-8, which license is in force and not suspended or revoked as of the particular time in question. </p>
<p class="indent">U. "Licensed Marriage and Family Therapy Associate (LMFTA)" means a person to whom a marriage and family therapy associate license has been issued under the Mississippi Code of 1972 as amended, Section 73-53-8, which license is in force and not suspended or revoked as of the particular time in question. </p>
<p class="indent">V. "Live Supervision" consists of a case related interactive face-to-face, either in- person or through a secure video conferencing platform meeting between the supervisor and supervisee, during which time the supervisor is physically or virtually present in the clinical setting with the supervisee. </p>
<p class="indent">W. "Marriage and Family Therapy" means the rendering of professional therapy services to individuals, families or couples, singly or in groups, and involves the professional application of psychotherapeutic and family systems theories and techniques in the delivery of therapy services to those persons. </p>
<p class="indent">X. "Offering" means an organized learning experience or course planned and designed to enhance knowledge, skills, and attitudes related to marriage and family therapy. </p>
<p class="indent">Y. "Person" means any individual, firm, corporation, partnership, organization or body politic. </p>
<p class="indent">Z. "Practice of Marriage and Family Therapy" means the rendering of professional marriage and family therapy services, to individuals, couples or families, singly or in groups, whether those services are offered directly to the general public or through organizations, either public or private, for a fee, monetary or otherwise. This involves assessment, diagnosis, identification, evaluation and treatment of emotional problems and conditions, whether cognitive, affective, or behavioral, resolving intrapersonal and interpersonal conflicts, and attempting to change perception, attitudes, and behaviors, all within the context of human relationship systems. Marriage and Family therapy includes, without being limited to, individual, group, couple, sexual, family and divorce therapy. It involves an applied understanding of the dynamics of marriage and family systems, including individual psychodynamics, the use of assessment instruments that evaluate individuals, couples and family members with regard to marriage and family functioning, and the use of psychotherapy and counseling. </p>
<p class="indent">AA. "Use of title or description of" means to hold oneself out to the public as a Licensed Marriage and Family Therapist (LMFT) or Licensed Marriage and Family Therapy Associate (LMFTA) through means of stating it on signs, mailboxes, address plates, stationery, announcements, calling cards, the internet or other instruments of professional identification. </p>
<p class="indent">Source: Miss. Code Ann. &#xa7;&#xa7;73-53-11(1) (c) and (j), 73-54-5, 73-54-11, and 73-54-19 (Supp. 2011). </p>
<p class="indent"><b>Part1903 Chapter 2: Licenses and the Licensing Process</b> </p>
<p class="indent">Rule 2.1 Types of Licenses </p>
<p class="indent">1. Licensed marriage and family therapist (LMFT) is the license granted to an individual who has met and maintained all the qualifications necessary for licensure to practice independently and the renewal of the license. </p>
<p class="indent">2. Licensed marriage and family therapy associate (LMFTA) is the license granted to an individual who has met and maintained all the qualifications necessary for licensure and for the renewal of the license. A licensed marriage and family therapy associate must practice in an agency setting under a "Board Approved" supervision contract. </p>
<p class="indent">Source: Miss. Code Ann. &#xa7;&#xa7;73-53-11(1) (c), 73-54-11 and 73-54-17(Supp. 2011). </p>
<p class="indent">Rule 2.2 REQUIREMENTS FOR LICENSURE AS A MARRIAGE AND FAMILY THERAPISTS </p>
<p class="indent">A. Prerequisite to Performance of Services as a Marriage and Family Therapists </p>
<p class="indent">All individuals not exempt from licensure are prohibited from performing services for which licensure is required by the State of Mississippi Marriage and Family Therapy Licensure Act of 1997, Title 73, Chapter 53 of the Mississippi Code of 1972 Annotated, as Amended, and these Rules and Regulations. They are also prohibited from holding themselves out to the public by any name, title or description described in the Marriage and Family Therapy Licensure Act and these Rules and Regulations. These regulations apply to all traditional and electronic approaches to marriage and family therapy. </p>
<p class="indent">B General Requirements </p>
<p class="indent">An individual seeking licensure as a Marriage and Family Therapist (LMFT) or a Marriage and Family Therapy Associate (LMFTA) shall submit to the Board, verified under oath, written evidence in form and content satisfactory to the Board, that the individual: </p>
<p class="indent">1. Is of good moral character as defined in these Rules and Regulations. Good moral character is a continuing requirement for licensure. </p>
<p class="indent">2. Has on file with the Board an acceptable criminal history records check, using finger print identification, by appropriate governmental authorities and an acceptable sex offender check, prescribed by the Board; </p>
<p class="indent">3. Has not engaged in any practice or conduct which violates the standards of conduct set forth in these regulations; </p>
<p class="indent">4. Meets all the qualifications required for licensure including, but not limited to, education and experience, passing examination scores, physical and mental abilities and has no addiction to or dependency upon alcohol, drugs, or other agent which may endanger the public or impair their ability or professional competence; </p>
<p class="indent">5. Has not acquired by deception or fraud, the education, experience, passing examination scores,<u> </u>professional references or any other qualifying factor used as a basis for licensure; </p>
<p class="indent">6. Does not have any previous or pending, complaints or disciplinary actions against them by any professional association or state of jurisdiction which have not been resolved to the satisfaction of the Board. It is the responsibility of the applicant to inform the Board if such items exist or have existed, and the Board may delay action on the licensure application until the complaints or disciplinary actions have been resolved and verified in writing to the satisfaction of the Board. If an applicant fails to reveal to the Board knowledge of previous or pending complaints or disciplinary actions, and the Board grants a license, the license will be revoked and the licensee will be disciplined by the Board; </p>
<p class="indent">7. Is at least twenty-one (21) years of age; </p>
<p class="indent">8. Meet all other requirements outlined in these rules and regulations; </p>
<p class="indent">C. Specific Requirements for Licensure as a Licensed Marriage and Family Therapist (LMFT) </p>
<p class="indent">1. <u>Education</u>: The individual seeking licensure must hold a masters or doctoral degree in marriage and family therapy from a COAMFTE accredited marriage and family therapy program; or holds a masters or doctoral degree in marriage and family therapy from a college or university program with candidacy status by COAMFTE which subsequently received COAMFTE accreditation. The applicant must have completed a clinical practicum in marriage and family therapy of no less than twelve (12) consecutive months that provided him or her face to face, either in-person or through a secure video conferencing platform, clinical practice with individuals, couples and families and allowed the applicant to apply classroom learning to actual marriage and family therapy practice situations in the field setting providing for live supervision. The practicum student must have completed a minimum of five hundred (500) client contact hours of which no less than three hundred (300) must be direct client contact hours and one hundred (100) must be relational direct client contact hours with couples and/or families and must have received one hundred (100) hours of supervision.<u> </u>The practicum experience must be supervised by an AAMFT approved supervisor or Supervisor Candidate under the supervision of an AAMFT Approved Supervisor. Practicum groups must be limited to a maximum of eight (8) supervisees per supervisor per group. An official transcript from the educational institution must be sent directly to the Board by the institution. </p>
<p class="indent">2. <u>Post Graduate Clinical Experience</u>: The individual under an <u> </u>approved supervision plan seeking licensure must complete two (2) years of documented clinical experience following the first qualifying graduate degree in the practice of marriage and family therapy within an agency, institution, or group practice setting. Application for licensure as a marriage and family therapist must occur within two (2) years of completion of post graduate clinical experience. An individual seeking status as a Licensed Marriage and Family Therapist who is not acquiring the documented clinical experience in an agency, institution, or a group practice setting will be practicing outside of the Board's Rules and Regulations, and his or her Plan of Supervision will not be approved by the MFT Discipline Specific Committee or the Board. This post graduate clinical experience must include a minimum of 1,000 documented face-to-face, either in-person or through a secure video conferencing platform, direct client contact hours. Documentation of compliance with this paragraph must be sent from the agency or person providing the clinical supervision directly to the Board. </p>
<p class="indent">3. <u>Supervision</u>: As required by these Rules and Regulations: an <u> </u>individual seeking licensure must: </p>
<p class="indent">a. The individual seeking licensure must complete two hundred (200) hours of marriage and family therapy supervision. A minimum of fifty (50) hours of the two hundred (200) hours of supervision must be individual supervision. Individual supervision is no more than two (2) marriage and family therapy supervisees or associates in a clinical setting during the supervision hour, which is fifty minutes. </p>
<p class="indent">b. Up to one (1) year of a COAMFTE approved doctoral internship may be counted toward the required two (2) years of post-graduate supervised clinical experience when the doctoral internship involved the provision of clinical marriage and family therapy services in a mental health treatment setting under the supervision of an AAMFT Approved Supervisor or AAMFT Supervisor Candidate under supervision of an AAMFT Approved Supervisor. Teaching or other non-clinical internship experiences will not be acceptable for satisfying this requirement. </p>
<p class="indent">c. Up to one hundred (100) hours of acceptable clinical supervision accumulated during graduate training may be counted toward the required two hundred (200) hours of clinical supervision. All one hundred (100) of the post graduate supervision hours must be completed with a Board Approved Supervisor. </p>
<p class="indent">d. At least one hundred (100) hours of the two hundred (200) hours of clinical supervision must be completed with an AAMFT approved supervisor. </p>
<p class="indent">e. The individual seeking licensure must complete and submit a Plan of Supervision (including the Supervisor's Statement), the <i>Application to Enter Into Contract for  Supervision Toward Licensure as a Marriage and Family Therapist</i>, and a non-refundable processing fee to the Board <i> </i>for approval. All plans of professional post-masters supervision <i>must be approved by the Board prior to the  beginning of said supervision, i.e., no retroactive approval of professional supervision will be granted except as provided in this section.</i> Supervisees will not receive more <i> </i>than four (4) hours credit for supervision completed prior to the Board's approval of the supervision plan. Supervisees should utilize this four (4) hours of supervision to collaboratively develop their supervision plan with their supervisor<b>.</b> The Board reserves the right to request explanations or plans of correction related to the submitted Plan of Supervision at any point. </p>
<p class="indent">f. Some individuals may be required, due to their circumstances, to work with two (2) different supervisors concurrently. This may be permitted as long as a Plan of Supervision has been completed with each individual supervisor and each Plan has been submitted and approved by the Board. </p>
<p class="indent">g. Evaluations of the supervisee are to be completed on evaluation forms available from the Board and submitted by the supervisor to the Board in accordance with the following schedule: </p>
<p class="indent">1. First evaluation is to be submitted ten (10) to twelve (12) months following Board approval of the Plan of Supervision. </p>
<p class="indent">2. The final evaluation is to be submitted when supervision is complete (twenty-four [24] to thirty- six [36] months following Board approval of the Plan of Supervision), accompanied by the Termination of Supervision Form, and completed Documentation of Supervision forms (all necessary forms are available from Board and at the Board's website). </p>
<p class="indent">h. The supervisory process requires an average of one (1) hour per week or two (2) hours of biweekly meetings of face-to- face supervision, either in-person or through a secure video conferencing platform, throughout a minimum period of twenty-four (24) consecutive months. The period of supervision may not exceed thirty-six (36) months. Under unusual circumstances (e.g., hurricane disaster, documented illness, etc.) a supervisee may apply for an extension of the supervisory process, which may be granted at the discretion of the Board. </p>
<p class="indent">i. Supervision means the direct clinical review, for the purposes of training or teaching by a supervisor, of the supervisee's interaction with a client. The supervision process may include time dedicated to personal and professional growth of the supervisee. Supervision provides guidance in administrative issues in the practice setting, continues and expands education in skills, professional competence and understanding of the marriage and family therapy profession, offers emotional support, and provides evaluation for purposes of the supervisee's growth, as well as administrative judgment relative to the supervisee's capacity for autonomous professional function. Supervision occurs through multiple methods, including live supervision, video/audiotape review, and case report. It must be a process clearly distinguishable from personal psychotherapy and is conducted in order to serve professional goals. Acceptable modes of supervision are as follows: </p>
<p class="indent">1. individual supervision <b><i> </i></b> </p>
<p class="indent">2. group supervision <b><i> </i></b> </p>
<p class="indent">j. The following is <b>not</b> acceptable marriage and family supervision: peer supervision; supervision by current or former family members or any other person with whom the nature of the personal relationship prevents, or makes difficult, the establishment of a professional supervisory relationship; administrative supervision; a primarily didactic process wherein techniques or procedures are taught in a group staff development, orientation to a field or program or role- playing of family relationships as a substitute for current clinical practice in an appropriate clinical situation. setting, classroom, workshop seminar, </p>
<p class="indent">k. The Board may accept up to one half (1/2) of the required one hundred (100) hours of post-graduate supervision obtained in another state toward licensure in MS so long as it is substantially equivalent to the standards set forth in the Board's rules and regulations. </p>
<p class="indent">4. <u>Working with a Board Approved Supervisor:</u> All postgraduate <u> </u>supervision must be received from an individual(s), who, at the time the supervision took place, was approved by the Board as a qualified supervisor and held a license to practice as a Marriage and Family Therapist. </p>
<p class="indent">a. To become a Board approved Supervisor, an individual (other than an AAMFT Approved Supervisor) must have completed a minimum of four (4) consecutive years of verifiable practice at the LMFT level, submitted an application for supervisory approval to the Board, and received notice from the Board that the application was approved. AAMFT Supervisor Candidates must have four (4) consecutive years of verifiable practice at the LMFT level and must be under supervision by an AAMFT Approved Supervisor. </p>
<p class="indent">b. An AAMFT Approved Supervisor may be recognized as approved by the Board upon: a) providing proof of licensure as a marriage and family therapist for two (2) years; b) submitting an application for supervisory approval to the Board; and c) providing documentation of current status as an AAMFT Approved Supervisor. </p>
<p class="indent">c. To be approved as a supervisor by the Board, an individual must have also completed a course in marriage and family therapy supervision approved by the Board with a minimum of twenty-four (24) contact hours. Supervision trainers (those teaching approved supervision courses) must be LMFTs and AAMFT Approved Supervisors. </p>
<p class="indent">d. All supervisors who have been approved by the Board, including supervisors who are AAMFT Approved Supervisors, are required to complete two (2) hours of MFT supervision continuing education every (2) two years. No supervision continuing education hours are required for the first renewal period. <b>All continuing education for </b> <b>supervision credit must be approved by the Board. </b>The Board will not approve self-directed learning projects/activities and/or distance learning/internet (online) learning courses for the supervision CE requirement. <b>Supervisor Refresher courses provided by AAMFT </b>or any division of the AAMFT<b> are automatically approved as </b> <b>meeting this requirement without Board action. </b> </p>
<p class="indent">e. All supervisors who have been approved by the Board, including supervisors who are AAMFT Approved Supervisors, are required to complete a Supervisor Renewal Form biennially (to be included with their Licensure Renewal Application if licensed in Mississippi) indicating they have met all continuing education requirements. </p>
<p class="indent">f. Approved supervisors are required to maintain copies of supervisee's evaluations and documentation pertaining to the supervisor/supervisee relationship for a period of two (2) calendar years following termination of the supervision contract with a supervisee. </p>
<p class="indent">g. Approved supervisors are required to work with the supervisee to complete a <b>Plan of Supervision</b> (including the <b>Supervisor's Statement</b>) and submit this to the Board. The Plan of Supervision must be approved by the Board before supervision can commence. Supervisees will not receive more than four (4) hours credit for supervision completed prior to the Board's approval of the supervision plan. Supervisees should utilize this four (4) hours of supervision to collaboratively develop their supervision plan with their supervisor<b>.</b> No plan of supervision will be approved if the approved supervisor is supervising more than <b>eight (8)</b> postgraduate licensure supervisees pursuing LMFT status in Mississippi at any given time. "While providing post- graduate supervision, board approved supervisors must maintain a current and active marriage and family therapy license that is in good standing with the Board." </p>
<p class="indent">h. Evaluations of the supervisee are to be completed by the supervisor during consultative sessions with the supervisee and submitted by the supervisor to the Board. </p>
<p class="indent">i. It is the responsibility of the approved supervisor to obtain a supervisor approval renewal form from the Board, to obtain the required continuing education verification, and to see that his or her approval is renewed on time. These forms are available online at the Board's website. Failure to receive a notice of renewal does not absolve the approved supervisor of his or her responsibility to renew this designation before the expiration date. </p>
<p class="indent">j. A list of Board approved supervisors is available online at the Board's website. Any individual having difficulty securing the services of a supervisor approved by the Board may contact the Board. When an individual wishes to be supervised by someone who is not an approved supervisor, the prospective supervisor will need to be eligible to become approved and will be required to complete the supervisory approval process prior to engaging in supervision. </p>
<p class="indent">5. <u>How to Change Supervisors</u>: Should it become necessary for a <u> </u>individual to change supervisors, the following steps must be followed to ensure continuity: </p>
<p class="indent">a. All relevant evaluation forms, including a Termination of Supervision Form, must be completed and submitted to the Board. The Termination of Supervision form must specify the number of hours of supervision completed, the period of supervision, and the reason for the dissolution of the supervisor/supervisee relationship. In cases where the supervisor is unable to complete this form (e.g., death) the supervisee must complete the termination of supervision form and provide such documentation as the Board deems necessary in support of the information contained on said form. </p>
<p class="indent">b. If supervision is to be continued with another approved supervisor, a new application (Application to Enter into Contract for Supervision toward Licensure as a Marriage and Family Therapist) and Plan of Supervision must be submitted to the Board for approval. <i>Only after receipt of  correspondence acknowledging that approval has been granted by the Board, may the new supervisory process commence. </i>The Board reserves the right to request <i> </i>explanations or plans of correction related to the Plan of Supervision at any point. No processing fee is required for this change. </p>
<p class="indent">6. <u>Application Process for Approval of Postgraduate Supervision: </u>It is <u> </u>the responsibility of the applicant for licensure to see that all forms, supporting documents, transcripts, etc., are completed, signed and notarized as required and sent to the Board in a timely manner. The Board will not consider an application as having been submitted until all the required items have been received by the Board. Applicants must submit to the Board, or ensure that the Board receives, the following items: </p>
<p class="indent">a. The original signed, notarized and completed Application to Enter into Contract for Supervision toward Licensure as a Marriage and Family Therapist or a Marriage and Family Therapy Associate form and processing fees. Application materials are available online at the Board's website. The Board does not accept personal checks for payment of fees; </p>
<p class="indent">b. A Supervisor's Statement form completed and signed by the approved supervisor; </p>
<p class="indent">c. A written, detailed Plan of Supervision; In this written, detailed plan of supervision, all points must be covered in sufficient detail for <i>review and approval </i>by the MFT Discipline Specific Committee<i>; </i>Specific topics to be addressed in the plan of supervision include, but are not limited to, the following: </p>
<p class="indent">1. The supervisee's and supervisor's orientation in this relationship, specifically addressing the purpose and goals of the supervisee and the frequency of supervision meetings for this particular supervision relationship; </p>
<p class="indent">2. The professional development of the supervisee, addressing issues related to the knowledge, skills, and values of the supervisee; </p>
<p class="indent">3. Issues related to supervisee's practice as a marriage and family therapist, including, but not limited to, the application of theories and models; the responsibilities of the supervisee to himself or herself, his or her clients, and the community; and the supervisee's commitment to continued learning and service; and, </p>
<p class="indent">4. This plan must be signed by both the supervisor and supervisee. </p>
<p class="indent">d. Official transcripts of graduate education mailed directly to the Board by the institution(s); </p>
<p class="indent">e. Recent picture of the applicant; and </p>
<p class="indent">f. The required processing fee. </p>
<p class="indent">7. For post graduate supervision begun with a supervisor prior to May 1, 2007, the individual providing clinical supervision must have been, at the time the supervision took place, a licensed marriage and family therapist, licensed psychologist, licensed certified social worker, licensed professional counselor, clinical nurse specialist, or psychiatrist with five (5) years' experience in his/her discipline and training in marriage and family therapy as determined by the Board Discipline Specific Committee. These individuals must have completed the application process for licensure by September 30, 2010. After September 30, 2010 these applicants must meet current standards prescribed below in Part 1903, Chapter 2, Rule 2.2, C below. </p>
<p class="indent">8. Supervision for licensure initiated after May 1, 2007 must be approved by the Board. </p>
<p class="indent">D. Examinations </p>
<p class="indent">The examination for licensing marriage and family therapist shall be the American Association of Marital and Family Therapy Regulatory Boards (AMFTRB) Examination in Marital and Family Therapy. </p>
<p class="indent">1. <b><u>Application Process</u></b> </p>
<p class="indent">a. An applicant for examination shall file an application, on forms supplied by the Board, at least seventy-five (75) calendar days prior to an examination date. An applicant is not eligible to take the examination until approved by the Board. </p>
<p class="indent">b. An applicant currently enrolled in a COAMFTE accredited graduate program may sit for the exam ninety (90) calendar days prior to graduation with the written approval of their program director. </p>
<p class="indent">c. An applicant may not be licensed as a Marriage and Family Therapy Associate or a Licensed Marriage and Family Therapist without passing the required examination. </p>
<p class="indent">d. The passing score on the examination shall be the passing score of the Board approved testing entity. </p>
<p class="indent">2. <b><u>Frequency of Examinations</u> </b> </p>
<p class="indent">Applicants seeking to retake the examination are required to follow AMFTRB guidelines regarding examination administration. </p>
<p class="indent"><b>3. </b> <b><u>Cost of Examination:</u></b><b> </b>The cost of the examination is dependent <b><u> </u></b>upon the fees charged by the testing service and is the responsibility of the applicant. </p>
<p class="indent">4. Release of Examination Scores to COAMFTE Accredited Programs: The Board will release examination scores for all accredited program graduates taking the examination to the accredited program director only if the candidate taking the examination has provided written permission for the Board to release said scores to the accredited program. </p>
<p class="indent">E. Application Requirements for Licensure as a Marriage and Family Therapy Associate (LMFTA) </p>
<p class="indent">The Board must have satisfactory evidence of the applicant successfully passing the AMFTRB Examination in Marital and Family Therapy before it will consider the application. In addition, applicants for licensure must submit to the Board, or ensure the Board receives, the following items: </p>
<p class="indent">1. The original signed, notarized and completed application form; </p>
<p class="indent">2. Official transcripts of graduate education mailed directly to the Board by the institution(s) if most current transcripts have not been previously submitted to the Board; </p>
<p class="indent">3. Documentation of a completed clinical practicum in marriage and family therapy of no less than twelve (12) consecutive months that provided him or her face to face clinical practice with individuals, couples and families and allowed the applicant to apply classroom learning to actual marriage and family therapy practice situations in the field setting providing for live supervision. The practicum student must have completed a minimum of five hundred (500) client contact hours of which no less than three hundred (300) must be direct client contact hours and one hundred (100) must be relational contact hours with couples and/or families and must have received one hundred (100) hours of supervision. The practicum experience must be supervised by an AAMFT Approved Supervisor or Supervisor Candidate under supervision by an AAMFT Approved Supervisor. Practicum groups must be limited to a maximum of eight (8) supervisees per supervisor per group. </p>
<p class="indent">4. Documentation of a passing score on the National Examination in Marital and Family Therapy prescribed by the Association for Marital and Family Therapy Regulatory Boards. </p>
<p class="indent">5. Documentation of an acceptable supervision plan that has been approved by the Board. </p>
<p class="indent">6. Three (3) acceptable letters of professional reference from licensed mental health professionals who have known the applicant for at least one (1) year, sent directly to the Board by the professional. </p>
<p class="indent">7. Recent picture of the applicant. </p>
<p class="indent">8. The applicant must have completed a statewide and nationwide, using fingerprint identification criminal history and background check and must have received a criminal background clearance within one-hundred eighty (180) calendar days of the completed application. This criminal history record information must be received by the Board directly from the appropriate governmental authority or authorities, not from the applicant. </p>
<p class="indent">9. The non-refundable application fee. </p>
<p class="indent">F. Application Requirements for Licensure as a Marriage and Family Therapist. The Board must have evidence of the applicant successfully passing the AMFTRB Examination in Marital and Family Therapy before it will consider the application. In addition, applicants for licensure must submit to the Board, or ensure the Board receives, the following items: </p>
<p class="indent">1. The original signed, notarized and completed application form; </p>
<p class="indent">2. Official transcripts of graduate education mailed directly to the Board by the institution(s) if up to date transcripts have not been previously submitted to the Board; </p>
<p class="indent">3. Documentation of a completed clinical practicum of no less than twelve (12) consecutive months that provided him or her face to face clinical practice with individuals, couples and families and allowed the applicant to apply classroom learning to actual marriage and family therapy practice situations in the field setting providing for live supervision. The practicum student must have completed a minimum of five hundred (500) client contact hours of which no less than three hundred (300) must be direct client contact hours and one hundred (100) must be relational direct client contact hours with couples and/or families and must have received 100 hours of supervision. The practicum experience must be supervised by an AAMFT Approved Supervisor or Supervisor Candidate under supervision by an AAMFT Approved Supervisor. Practicum groups must be limited to a maximum of eight (8) supervisees per supervisor per group; </p>
<p class="indent">4. Documentation of a passing score on the National Examination in Marital and Family Therapy prescribed by the Association for Marital and Family Therapy Regulatory Boards; </p>
<p class="indent">5. Documentation of clinical experience acceptable to the Board, a final supervision evaluation acceptable to the Board (the first evaluation must have already been submitted to the Board by the supervisor), and all necessary Termination of Supervision Forms must be submitted directly to the Board by the appropriate agency and/or supervisor(s); </p>
<p class="indent">6. Three (3) acceptable letters of professional reference from licensed mental health professionals who have known the applicant for at least one (1) year, sent directly to the Board by the professional. The persons documenting the clinical experience and supervision may NOT be used for the letters of professional reference; </p>
<p class="indent">7. Recent picture of the applicant, if a picture has not been previously submitted to the Board; </p>
<p class="indent">8. An acceptable criminal history records check, finger print and an acceptable sex offender check, by appropriate governmental authorities as prescribed by the Board. The applicant must have completed a statewide and nationwide, using fingerprint identification,<u> </u>criminal history and background check and must have received criminal background clearance within one hundred eighty (180) calendar days immediately before the completed application is filed with the Board. This criminal history record information must be received by the Board directly from the appropriate governmental authority or authorities, not from the applicant; </p>
<p class="indent">9. The non-refundable application fee. </p>
<p class="indent">G. Licensure by Endorsement </p>
<p class="indent">1. Licensed Marriage and Family Therapy Associate </p>
<p class="indent">The Board does not license Marriage and Family Therapy Associates by endorsement. Applicants seeking state licensure as a Marriage and Family Therapy Associate must meet all current Board requirements. </p>
<p class="indent">2. Licensed Marriage and Family Therapist by Endorsement for Nonresidents </p>
<p class="indent">The Board may issue a license by examination of credentials to any applicant licensed at least one </p>
<p class="indent">(1) year for independent practice as a marriage and family therapist in another state that has such requirements for the license that the board is of the opinion that the applicant is competent to engage in the practice of marriage and family therapy. These would include minimum education requirements, work experience, and clinical supervision requirements equivalent to those in Mississippi. The applicant must apply on forms prescribed by the board, have passed the National Examination in Marital and Family Therapy, and pay the licensure fee as prescribed. The applicant must not have a record of disciplinary actions or pending disciplinary actions. If the applicant has pending disciplinary actions, the board will take no action on the application until those have been resolved </p>
<p class="indent">Requirements for endorsement for Nonresidents </p>
<p class="indent">a. The original signed, notarized and completed application; </p>
<p class="indent">b. Licensure verification form mailed directly to the Board from the state or jurisdiction in which the current license is held. </p>
<p class="indent">c. A recent picture of the applicant; </p>
<p class="indent">d. An acceptable statewide and nationwide criminal history and background check, using fingerprint identification, received within ninety (90) calendar days immediately before the completed application is filed with the Board. This criminal history record information check must be received by the Board directly from the appropriate governmental authority or authorities, not from the applicant. </p>
<p class="indent">e. The non-refundable application fee. </p>
<p class="indent">3. Licensure through Endorsement for Residents </p>
<p class="indent">(Based on Section 73-50-2 of the Mississippi Code of 1972 designated Universal Recognition of Occupational License Act), The Board shall issue a license to an applicant who has established residence and held an independent license to practice marriage and family therapy for one (1) year in another state in which there were minimum education, work experience, examination, and clinical supervision requirements and the applicant has not committed any act that would have been grounds for refusal, suspension or revocation of a license or any disqualifying criminal record. Additionally, the applicant did not voluntarily surrender a license because of negligence or intentional misconduct and has no complaint, allegation or investigation pending. </p>
<p class="indent">The Board shall issue or deny the license within one hundred and twenty (120) calendar days after receiving an application. Should the Board require more than two (2) weeks to process, The Board shall issue a temporary practice permit within thirty (30) calendar days after receiving the application. The applicant will practice under the temporary practice permit until license is granted or denied. The temporary practice permit will expire within three hundred and sixty (360) days. (See Rule 3.5 for further clarification). </p>
<p class="indent">a. Requirements for Licensure through Endorsement for Residents </p>
<p class="indent">i. The original signed, notarized and completed application form; </p>
<p class="indent">ii. The original signed, notarized and completed Universal Recognition of Occupational License affidavit; </p>
<p class="indent">iii. Licensure verification form mailed directly to the Board from the state in which the current license is held; </p>
<p class="indent">iv. A recent picture of the applicant; </p>
<p class="indent">v. Proof of residence; </p>
<p class="indent">vi. An acceptable statewide and nationwide criminal history and background check, using fingerprint identification, received within ninety (90) calendar days immediately before the completed application is filed with the Board. This criminal history record information check must be received by the Board directly from the appropriate governmental authority or authorities, not from the applicant; and, </p>
<p class="indent">vii. The non-refundable application fee. </p>
<p class="indent">Source: Miss. Code Ann. &#xa7;&#xa7;73-53-11(1)(c), (d), (e), (g), (k), (<i>l</i>), (n), (o) and (u), 73-53-15, 73- 54-7, 73-54-11, 73-54-13, 73-54-17, 73-54-19, 73-54-23, 73-54-27(4) and 73-54- 29(4)(Supp. 2011). </p>
<p class="indent">Rule 2.3 THE APPLICATION PROCESS </p>
<p class="indent">A. Making the Application for Licensure </p>
<p class="indent">1. The current rules and regulations regarding licensure, as well as all application forms, are available online at the Board website, <u>http://www.swmft.ms.gov/swmft</u>. The applicant may also request an official application packet for licensure as a marriage and family therapist, and a copy of the current rules and regulations regarding licensure from the Board for a fee as prescribed in Part 1903, Chapter 5, Rule 5.2. </p>
<p class="indent">2. Additional copies of the required forms may be made as needed. </p>
<p class="indent">3. It is the responsibility of the applicant to see that all forms, supporting documents, references, fees, transcripts, etc. are completed, signed and notarized as required and sent to the Board in a timely manner. </p>
<p class="indent">4. The Board will not consider an application as complete until all forms, documentation, references, fees, transcripts, etc. have been received by the Board. </p>
<p class="indent">5. Inaccurate information or misrepresentation of facts on any form submitted to the board may result in a denial of licensure or revocation of the license at a later date. </p>
<p class="indent">B. Board Consideration of Licensure Applications </p>
<p class="indent">1. The Board will consider all applications under the rules and regulations for licensure that are in effect on the date the application was received by the Board. </p>
<p class="indent">2. The Board will consider the applications when all related items are in the file. If the Board approves the application, the applicant will be notified in writing. If the application is not approved, the applicant will be notified in writing of the reason(s). </p>
<p class="indent">3. If the application is approved, the board will notify the applicant of the amount of the initial license fee that is due, depending on the time during the year when the application was approved. The license fee must be paid in full before the license is issued. </p>
<p class="indent">4. Once the license fee is paid in full, the Board will assign a license number and issue the applicant an official certificate. </p>
<p class="indent">C. Disposition of Incomplete or Deficient Applications </p>
<p class="indent">1. Removal of Deficiencies: </p>
<p class="indent">If a preliminary review of the application by the Board reveals that the application is incomplete or has a minor deficiency, the applicant will be notified in writing. The applicant will be given six (6) months from the date of the first notice to remedy the problem while the application is held on active status by the Board. Applicants may, at the discretion of the Board, be granted one (1) additional extension, not to exceed six (6) months, for unusual extenuating circumstances upon a written request, with full explanation of circumstances, submitted to the Board before the expiration of the initial six (6) months extension. </p>
<p class="indent">2. Abandoned Applications: </p>
<p class="indent">Incomplete application on file for more than thirty-six (36) months from the date the Plan of Supervision was approved by the Board or applications that have not been completed or made sufficient during the extended time granted by the board, will be declared abandoned by the Board and will be given no further consideration. </p>
<p class="indent">a. Any incomplete or missing information, documentation or fees shall render the application incomplete. No license shall be issued unless all application requirements have been met. Incomplete applications will be considered abandoned after sixty (60) calendar days from the date of the approval by the Board, to pay the initial license fee. Any fees paid shall not be refunded. </p>
<p class="indent">b. Submission of New Application: Once an application has been declared abandoned by the Board, the applicant may submit a completely new application for licensure under the rules and regulations in effect at the time the new application is submitted. </p>
<p class="indent">Source: Miss. Code Ann. &#xa7;&#xa7;73-53-11(1) (c), (d) and (e), 73-53-15(2), 73-54-11(1), 73-54-13 and 73-54-17 (Supp. 2011). </p>
<p class="indent">Rule 2.4 Status of License </p>
<p class="indent">A. Active or in Good Standing: Is the status held by a licensee who has complied, and is in compliance, with all of the licensure and licensure renewal requirements of the Board and has no disciplinary actions against the license or licensee. Licensees on active status and in good standing may utilize the Board's online renewal system. </p>
<p class="indent">B. Denied: The Board determines that the applicant or licensee has failed to meet any requirement or standard established by the Mississippi <i>Marriage </i> <i>and Family Therapy Licensure Act of </i>1997, as amended, and/or these Rules and Regulation or the applicant or licensee has failed to comply with the laws, rules and regulations pertaining to the practice of marriage and family therapy. </p>
<p class="indent">C. Revoked: Disciplinary action taken by the Board extinguishing or terminating a license or certificate and all rights, privileges and authority previously conferred and associated with the license or certificate. The person may not practice marriage and family therapy during the time the license is revoked unless he or she is exempt from the requirements of licensure by the Board as provided by Section 73-54-9 of the Mississippi Code of 1972 as amended. A person whose license has been revoked by the Board may apply for reinstatement as ordered by the Board. The Board may reinstate the license if satisfactory evidence is submitted to the Board proving that all conditions for reinstatement of the license, if any, have been met. </p>
<p class="indent">D. Suspended: Action against a license rendering such license, and all rights, privileges and authority previously conferred and associated with the license, without force and effect for a period of time as determined by the Board. The person may not practice marriage and family therapy during the time the license is suspended unless he or she is exempt from the requirement of licensure by the Board as provide by Section 73-54-9 of the Mississippi Code of 1972 as amended. A person whose license has been suspended by the Board may seek reinstatement of the license as ordered by the Board. The Board may reinstate the license if satisfactory evidence is submitted to the Board proving that all conditions for reinstatement of the license, if any, have been met. </p>
<p class="indent">E. Lapsed: The status of a license of an individual who has failed to renew the license as of the deadline for renewing (that is, by September 30 of the expiration year of the license). A license that has lapsed is no longer valid and the individual's privilege to practice marriage and family therapy terminates. A licensee may not practice marriage and family therapy during the time his or her license is lapsed. A renewal submitted to the Board less than thirty (30) calendar days after the expiration date of the license is considered a late renewal and will be assessed a late fee. A license lapsed for more than thirty (30) calendar days must be reinstated under the reinstatement process. The license may be reinstated within a two (2) year period by following the reinstatement process. A license that has lapsed for more than two (2) years cannot be renewed or reinstated. The licensee must apply for a new license and meet the conditions for licensure under the laws and requirements set forth in the rules and regulations that are in effect at the time the new application is received by the Board. </p>
<p class="indent">F. Inactive: A license that has been placed in an inoperative or non-working status in accordance with Board rules and based upon the licensee's certification to the Board that he or she will not practice or offer to practice marriage and family therapy in Mississippi. A Licensed Marriage and Family Therapist may request in writing on the forms provided by the Board that his or her license be placed on inactive status. The Board will consider the request and will notify the licensee of its decision within sixty (60) calendar days of receiving the written request for inactive status. Licensed Marriage and Family Therapy Associates are not eligible for inactive status. </p>
<p class="indent">During the period of inactive status, the individual is prohibited from practicing marriage and family therapy or representing or presenting himself or herself as having a license, practice privilege, certificate or registration that entitles one to practice as a marriage and family therapist in Mississippi. </p>
<p class="indent">A Licensed Marriage and Family Therapist granted inactive status shall be excused from paying renewal fees until he or she notifies the Board in writing of his or her intention to resume active practice. If a licensee fails to return to active status within two (2) years of being placed on inactive status, the licensee may request an extension in writing on forms provided by the Board for an additional two (2) years. If the licensee does not request an extension in writing on forms provided by the Board or no extension has been granted in writing by the Board, the license will be deemed lapsed on September 30<sup>th</sup>following the end of the inactive status period. The licensee must then apply for a new license under the requirements set forth in the laws, rules and regulations that are in effect at the time the new application is received by the Board. </p>
<p class="indent">Each Marriage and Family Therapist licensee on inactive status must provide the Board with satisfactory evidence of having obtained acceptable/approved continuing education hours that would have been required had he or she been licensed in an Active status. </p>
<p class="indent">Disciplinary action will be taken against a licensee on inactive status who performs marriage and family therapy in the state of Mississippi or presents him/herself as a licensed marriage and family therapist. </p>
<p class="indent">Source: Miss. Code Ann. &#xa7;&#xa7;73-53-11(1) (c), (e) and (k), 73-53-23(1), 73-54-11(1), 73-54-13, 73-54-17, 73-54-27 and 73-54-29 (Supp. 2011). </p>
<p class="indent"><b>Part1903 Chapter 3 Professional Standards of Practice and Code of Conduct </b> </p>
<p class="indent">Rule 3.1 PROFESSIONAL IDENTIFICATION AS A MARRIAGE AND FAMILY THERAPIST </p>
<p class="indent">A. Titles and Abbreviations </p>
<p class="indent">Persons licensed to practice marriage and family therapy in Mississippi may use the title "Licensed Marriage and Family Therapist" and they may use the letters LMFT as a professional identification following their name as it appears on the license. Persons licensed to practice as Marriage and Family Therapy Associates in Mississippi may use the title "Licensed Marriage and Family Therapy Associate" and they may use the letters LMFTA as professional identification following their name as it appears on the license. </p>
<p class="indent">B. Display of License </p>
<p class="indent">The certificate of licensure issued by the Board and the current verification of renewal shall be displayed at all times in the licensee's place of practice. Official duplicates of the license may be obtained from the board if more than one copy is needed. </p>
<p class="indent">C. Change in Name </p>
<p class="indent">It is the responsibility of the licensee to notify the Board promptly, no later than thirty (30) calendar days following the change of name, of any change in their name and to request a new certificate of licensure showing the appropriate name. All requests for a name changed must be made in writing, signed and notarized, and accompanied by a certified copy of the legal document which changed the name, and the appropriate fee or administrative cost. Licensees will be in violation of the standards of practice if they practice using a name different from the one appearing on their license certificate, and will be subject to disciplinary action by the Board. </p>
<p class="indent">D. Use of Technology Assisted Marriage and Family Therapy Services </p>
<p class="indent">1. Definitions </p>
<p class="indent">Clients - the individual, couple, family, group, or organization that receives marriage and family therapy services from an individual or co-therapy team of marriage and family therapists. </p>
<p class="indent">Technology-Assisted Services - therapy or supervision services provided through electronic means utilizing a secure video platform. </p>
<p class="indent">In-person - refers to interactions in which the marriage and family therapist and the client are face-to-face either in-person or via secure video conferencing platform. </p>
<p class="indent">Remote - refers to the provision of a service that is received at a different site from where the marriage and family therapist is physically located. </p>
<p class="indent">2. The practice of LMFTA or LMFT with an individual in the state of Mississippi or any other state through technology-assisted services, regardless of the location of the therapist, shall constitute the practice of marriage and family therapy and be subject to Rules and Regulations of the state where they are providing services. Marriage and family therapists providing technology-assisted services shall take all necessary measures to ensure compliance with the relevant standards and ethics. </p>
<p class="indent">Marriage and family therapists who choose to provide technology- assisted services shall: </p>
<p class="indent">a. Determine that technologically-assisted services or supervision are appropriate for clients or supervisees, considering professional, intellectual, emotional, and physical needs. </p>
<p class="indent">b. Inform clients or supervisees of the potential risks and benefits associated with technologically-assisted services, advise clients and supervisees in writing of these risks, and advise them of both the therapist's and the clients/supervisees' responsibilities for minimizing such risks </p>
<p class="indent">c. Choose technological platforms that adhere to standards of best practices related to confidentiality and quality of services, and Inform clients/supervisees of the limitations and protections offered by the therapist's or supervisor's technology. that meet applicable laws. </p>
<p class="indent">d. Ensure that all documentation containing identifying or otherwise sensitive information which is electronically stored and/or transferred is done using technology that adheres to standards of best practices related to confidentiality and quality of services, and that meet applicable laws. Inform clients/supervisees of the limitations and protections offered by the therapist's or supervisor's technology. </p>
<p class="indent">e. Follow all laws regarding location of practice and services, and do not use technologically-assisted means for practicing outside of their allowed jurisdictions. </p>
<p class="indent">f. Ensure that they are trained and competent in the use of all chosen technology-assisted professional services and choose suitably advanced and current technology in order to best service the professional needs of clients and supervisees. </p>
<p class="indent">g. Take reasonable steps to verify the identity of clients/supervisees, particularly at first meeting. </p>
<p class="indent">Source: Miss. Code Ann. &#xa7;&#xa7;73-53-11(1) (c), (g), (k) and (2), 73-54-3 and 73-54-11(1) (2008 &amp; Supp. 2011). </p>
<p class="indent"><b>Part1903 Chapter 4 Continuing Education and Licensure Renewal; Reinstatement </b> </p>
<p class="indent">Rule 4.1 CONTINUING EDUCATION </p>
<p class="indent">A. Purpose </p>
<p class="indent">The purpose of this section is to establish the continuing education requirements for licensed marriage and family therapists (LMFT). The LMFT license must be renewed biennially. Licensed marriage and family therapy associates (LMFTA) are not required to participate in continuing education. The continuing education offerings for each discipline (social workers and marriage and family therapists) are approved independently. Licensees should NOT assume that an approved offering for one discipline is also approved for the other discipline. The MBOE website maintains separate lists of approved continuing education offerings for social workers and marriage and family therapists. The primary objective of continuing education must be to maintain and improve the quality of professional services in marriage and family therapy provided to the public; maintain and improve the therapist's knowledge of current research, techniques, and practice; and provide other resources which will improve skill and competence in marriage and family therapy. A licensee will receive credit only for continuing education programs or activities approved by the MFT Continuing Education Committee. Approved programs will be listed on the Continuing Education Offering for MFTs page on the Board's website. Continuing education hours must be relevant to the practice of marriage and family therapy as determined by the Board in accordance with the criteria cited at Part 1903, Chapter 4, Rule 4.1(H) of these Rules and Regulations. </p>
<p class="indent">B. Requirements </p>
<p class="indent">All licensed marriage and family therapists must complete twenty-four (24) hours of approved continuing education during every two (2) year license period. No continuing education hours are required for the first renewal period. The Board will accept up to twelve (12) hours of approved distance learning/internet (online) continuing education hours toward the twenty- four (24) hours. Four (4) out of the twenty-four (24) must be approved MFT professional ethics hours. The Board will approve self-directed learning projects and/or distance learning/internet (online) learning courses for the MFT ethics CE requirement for up to two (2) MFT ethics hours of the total twelve (12) allowable distance learning/internet provided hours. All Board approved supervisors, including those with AAMFT Approved Supervisor standing, must complete two (2) approved hours of MFT supervision continuing education each renewal period. No supervision continuing education hours are required for the first renewal period after obtaining board approved supervisor status. The Board will approve self-directed learning projects and/or distance learning/internet (online) learning courses for up to two (2) of the supervision CE requirement of the total twelve (12) allowable approved distance learning/internet (online). It is the responsibility of each licensee and supervisor to determine in advance that the continuing education activity has been approved by the MFT Continuing Education Committee. </p>
<p class="indent">C. Board Continuing Education Committee </p>
<p class="indent">The MFT Continuing Education Committee shall consist of designated members of the MFT Discipline Specific Committee. The Board may also select non-Board members who they deem qualified, to serve on the MFT Continuing Education Committee. At least one (1) member of the committee must be a professional educator from a COAMFTE MFT program. The chair of the committee will be a member of the MFT Discipline Specific Committee. </p>
<p class="indent">D. Determination of Clock Hour Credits </p>
<p class="indent">MFT Continuing Education Committee approved offerings shall be credited with one (1) continuing education clock-hour credit for each one (1) clock- hour spent in the continuing education activity, unless otherwise designated by the Board. Time devoted to registration, organizational business, breakfasts, luncheons, dinners, or other refreshments shall not be counted as instructional or continuing education credit time. </p>
<p class="indent">E. Types of Acceptable Continuing Education </p>
<p class="indent">Credit will be given only for continuing education programs or activities approved by the MFT Continuing Education Committee. To be acceptable to the MFT Continuing Education Committee continuing education offerings for LMFTs must conform to at least one (1) of the seven (7) content areas specified below under Criteria for Approval of Continuing Education Activities. A qualified presenter is someone found by the Board to be a professional in marriage and family therapy, another mental health discipline, or another profession with information, knowledge, and skills relevant to the practice of marriage and family therapy. </p>
<p class="indent">The following types of continuing education activities are acceptable <b>provided that the standards set forth below under Criteria for Approval of Continuing Education Activities have been met</b>: </p>
<p class="indent">1. Continuing education activities related to the practice of marriage and family therapy offered by the American Association of Marriage and Family Therapy (AAMFT) and any of its divisions, including the Mississippi Association of Marriage and Family Therapy (MAMFT); Mississippi Board of Examiners for Social Workers and Marriage and Family Therapists; and the Association of Marital and Family Therapy Regulatory Boards are automatically approved by the MFT Continuing Education Committee. </p>
<p class="indent">2. Successful completion (grade B or better), from a regionally accredited college/ university, of a graduate course specific to the practice of marriage and family therapy. One (1) academic semester hour will be equivalent to five (5) hours of continuing education hours; </p>
<p class="indent">3. Teaching in a graduate school of marriage and family therapy. Credit will be applied at the rate of three (3) hours for every credit hour taught; teaching may count for no more than twelve (12)<u> </u>hours of the biannual continuing education requirement; </p>
<p class="indent">4. Presenting workshops, seminars, or lectures that are approved for CE credit for LMFTs will be awarded CEU credit at the rate of two (2) hours of credit for each hour of presentation (if the same offering is presented multiple times during the two (2) year renewal period, the continuing education credit hours may only be counted the first time the offering was presented); </p>
<p class="indent">5. Self-Directed Learning Projects and/or Distance Learning/Internet (Online) Learning Courses: Continuing education hours for distance learning/internet learning courses will only be granted for courses approved in advance by the MFT CE Committee. The MFT CE Committee will grant continuing education hours only after completion of the course and proof of successful completion of post- test, course examination, and/or evaluation from the course provider. No more than<ins> twelve (12)</ins> hours of the twenty-four (<ins>24)</ins> required hours may be earned in this manner during each two (2) year renewal period. No more than two (2) of those twelve (12) online hours can be applied to the four (4) required ethics continuing education. </p>
<p class="indent">6. Continuing education credit may be earned by Board approved supervisors for clinical supervision of individuals with active Supervision Plans on file with the Board. Supervision may count for no more than ten (10) hours of the biennial continuing education requirement, but not count toward the two <u>(2)</u> hours required for Board approved supervisors to maintain their approved supervisor status; and, </p>
<p class="indent">7. An author of a book or peer reviewed article which, as determined by the Board, enhances a marriage and family therapist's knowledge or skill may be granted continuing education credit not to exceed one-half (1/2) of the biannual continuing education requirement. </p>
<p class="indent">8. Supervised Self Directed Learning Groups </p>
<p class="indent">Licensed marriage and family therapists may earn up to eight (8) continuing education hours for each renewal period through participation in a Board approved supervised self-directed learning group. In order to receive Board approval the following requirements must be met: </p>
<p class="indent">a. The group must be led by a Board Approved supervisor. </p>
<p class="indent">b. A supervision plan documenting the names and license numbers of all participants, proposed learning objectives and an outline of the process for meeting each learning objective must be approved in advance by the MFT Continuing Education Committee. Only plans meeting the criteria for approval of continuing education activities listed in Part 1903, Chapter 4, Rule 4.1(H) of these rules and regulations will be approved. Failure to submit a plan within the sixty (60) calendar day time period could result in disapproval of the activity for continuing education credit. </p>
<p class="indent">c. Each participant must complete a post evaluation report documenting the effectiveness of the group learning experience and turn it in to the Approved Supervisor leading the group. This report should include evidence that the learning objectives were met. The Approved Supervisor shall maintain these reports for a period of four (4) years following completion of the supervised self-directed learning group experience. </p>
<p class="indent">d. Participation in each supervised self-directed learning group shall be limited to no less than four (4) and no more than eight (8) participants and a State Approved Supervisor. </p>
<p class="indent">e. The supervised self-directed learning group supervisor must issue each participant a signed certificate of completion containing the participants name, license number, number of hours completed, dates of attendance, and MFT CE approval number. </p>
<p class="indent">f. MFT ethics CE hours and Approved Supervisor CE hours will not be awarded for participation in any self-directed learning projects. </p>
<p class="indent">g. The fee for supervised self-directed learning group approval shall be the same as the fee for becoming a Board Approved Continuing Education Provider. </p>
<p class="indent">F. Application Procedure to Become a Board Approved Continuing Education Sponsor </p>
<p class="indent">Appropriate providers may apply to the MFT Continuing Education Committee to become approved providers of continuing education activities. Providers may include, but are not limited to, colleges and universities, individuals, mental health agencies, private mental health organizations, and professional organizations. Home study programs are encouraged to apply for approved provider status. </p>
<p class="indent">Applicants for approved provider status must complete the necessary application and submit it to the MFT Continuing Education Committee and pay any associated fees (see section IX.B) required by the Board. The MFT Continuing Education Committee will evaluate the application and notify the applicant in writing regarding the approval of that application. </p>
<p class="indent">If granted, Approved provider status will expire on December 31 of each year. However, if an initial application is approved after September 1, the status will expire December 31 of the following year. Approved providers must reapply each year in order to maintain their approved provider status. </p>
<p class="indent">Approved providers are not required to submit an additional application fee per offering during their "approved provider" year. However, they must submit the appropriate application for each individual continuing education offering to the MFT Continuing Education Committee for review and approval. Each approved offering will be issued an approval number that must appear on the certificate provided to the participant. All applications should be received at least sixty (60) calendar days in advance of the offering in order to receive full consideration by the Committee. Failure to submit a plan within the sixty (60) calendar day time period could result in disapproval of the organization or individual as an approved provider of continuing education. </p>
<p class="indent">G. Approval Procedure for any organization or individual that is not a Board approved sponsor or designated provider </p>
<p class="indent">Any organization or individual that is not a Board approved continuing education provider must submit an application for each continuing education offering sixty (60) calendar days prior to the date of the offering. The applications must be made, in writing, to the MFT Continuing Education Committee, which reviews and pre-approves continuing education. <b>NO RETROACTIVE APPROVALS WILL BE MADE.</b> Applications for or questions about said approval should be sent to the following address: </p>
<p class="center">Mississippi Board of Examiners for Social Workers and</p>
<p class="center">Marriage and Family Therapists</p>
<p class="center">MFT Continuing Education Committee</p>
<p class="center">P.O. Box 4508</p>
<p class="center">Jackson, MS 39296-4508</p>
<p class="center">601-987-6806</p>
<p class="indent">The Board's office or the Chair of the MFT Continuing Education Committee may be contacted for application forms or questions about the procedure. </p>
<p class="indent">H. Criteria for Approval of Continuing Education Activities </p>
<p class="indent">Continuing education hours must be relevant to the practice of marriage and family therapy as determined by the MFT Continuing Education Committee, with an emphasis on systemic approaches or the theory, research or practice of psychotherapy work with couples or families. Continuing education for marriage and family therapy generally evolves from the following area and must be related to <b>at least one</b> of the following seven (7) areas: </p>
<p class="indent">1. Theoretical Knowledge of Marriage and Family Therapy. Examples of acceptable offering content in this area include, but are not limited to, the historical development, theoretical and empirical foundations, and contemporary conceptual directions of the field of marriage and family therapy; </p>
<p class="indent">2. Clinical Knowledge of Marriage and Family Therapy. Courses in this area cover: </p>
<p class="indent">a. couple and family therapy practice related conceptually to theory; </p>
<p class="indent">b. contemporary issues, which include but are not limited to gender, violence, addictions, and abuse, in the treatment of individuals, couples, and families from a relational/systemic perspective; </p>
<p class="indent">c. a wide variety of presenting clinical problems related to the practice of marriage and family theory and practice; </p>
<p class="indent">d. issues of gender and sexual functioning, sexual orientation, and sex therapy as they relate to couple, marriage and family therapy theory and practice; and/or </p>
<p class="indent">e. diversity and discrimination as it relates to couple and family therapy theory and practice. </p>
<p class="indent">3. Assessment and Treatment in Marriage and Family Therapy. Acceptable offering content in this area incorporates a relational/systemic perspective on topics such as, but not limited to, psychopharmacology, physical health and illness, traditional psychodiagnostic categories, and the assessment and treatment of major mental health issues. </p>
<p class="indent">4. Individual, Couple, and Family Development. Acceptable offering content in this area focuses on individual, couple, and/or family development across the lifespan. </p>
<p class="indent">5. Professional Identity and Ethics in Marriage and Family Therapy. <b>Generic education in ethics does not meet this standard.</b> Acceptable content in this area includes: </p>
<p class="indent">a. professional identity of the marriage and family therapist, including professional socialization, scope of practice, professional organizations, licensure and certification; </p>
<p class="indent">b. ethical issues related to the profession of marriage and family therapy and the practice of individual, couple and family therapy; </p>
<p class="indent">c. the AAMFT Code of Ethics, confidentiality issues, the legal responsibilities and liabilities of clinical practice and research, family law, record keeping, reimbursement, and the business aspects of practice as these relate to the practice of marriage and family therapy; </p>
<p class="indent">d. the interface between marriage and family therapist responsibility and the professional, social, and political context of treatment. </p>
<p class="indent">6. Research in Marriage and Family Therapy: Content in this area includes significant material on research in couple and family therapy; focus on content such as research methodology, data analysis and the evaluation of research, and include quantitative and qualitative research. </p>
<p class="indent">7. Supervision in Marriage and Family Therapy: Content in this area includes studies in theory and techniques of supervision as well as ethical and legal issues, case management, and topics relative to the specific supervised training. </p>
<p class="indent">I. Documenting and Reporting </p>
<p class="indent">1. <u>Record Keeping</u>: The licensee shall maintain for four (4) years their <u> </u>own records and official verification of the continuing education they have completed. The Board will not maintain continuing education files for <del>the</del> licensees. </p>
<p class="indent">2. <u>Reporting Continuing Education</u>: The continuing education hours <u> </u>will be reported once every two years as part of the license renewal process. No continuing education hours are required for the first renewal period. </p>
<p class="indent">3. <u>Provider Responsibility</u>: It is the responsibility of each organization <u> </u> or provider of continuing education to 1) provide the Board with verified list of participants including license number and the number of earned CE hours, and 2) provide the attendee with a written statement, verification, or certificate of attendance or CEU certificate which verifies completion of the offering. The attendee's verification must include the following information: </p>
<p class="indent">a. Name of attendee </p>
<p class="indent">b. Name of offering </p>
<p class="indent">c. Date of offering </p>
<p class="indent">d. Provider's name </p>
<p class="indent">e. Program approval number assigned by MFT Continuing Education Committee </p>
<p class="indent">f. Signature of organizer/sponsor or designee </p>
<p class="indent">g. <ins>Number</ins> of continuing education hours awarded </p>
<p class="indent">4. <u>Licensee Responsibility</u>: It is the responsibility of the licensee to <u> </u>obtain a certificate, transcript or other official document from the approved provider showing the appropriate information. The supporting documentation verifying the continuing education must be kept by the licensee and not sent to the Board unless the Board makes a request in writing for the documentation as a part of the audit process. </p>
<p class="indent">J. Random Audit of Continuing Education Documents </p>
<p class="indent">1. The Board <del>will</del> may annually audit or cause to be audited a minimum of twenty percent (20%) of the continuing education reports accompanying the renewal applications. Licensees whose reports are audited will be required to provide a copy of the official documentation of their continuing education activities. If a licensee fails to provide the Board in a timely manner (not to exceed thirty (30) calender days following the time they are notified of the audit) with official documentation of the total hours listed on their renewal application, the license will be suspended following written notification from the Board and will remain suspended pending further Board action. </p>
<p class="indent">2. If, during the audit, the Board disqualifies any of the documented continuing education hours and the licensee does not have sufficient acceptable hours remaining for that renewal period, the Board, at its discretion, may renew the license under the conditions that the continuing education hours will be obtained within six (6) months of the notice of deficiency. Continuing education hours acquired to meet the deficiency may not be applied to any other renewal period. If the licensee does not rectify the deficiency within that six (6) month period, the license will be subject to disciplinary action, including revocation, for failure to comply with the continuing education requirements. </p>
<p class="indent">K. Re-evaluation of Continuing Education </p>
<p class="indent">A licensee who believes that evidence of continuing education was appraised incorrectly by the Board, may make a written request for reevaluation to the Board within thirty (30) calendar days of the Board's finding. Verbal requests will not be honored. </p>
<p class="indent">L. Waiver of Continuing Education Requirements and Request for Extension of Time to Complete Continuing Education Requirements </p>
<p class="indent">1. The Board may waive continuing education requirements to a licensee who was not engaged in the practice of marriage and family therapy during a given continuing education renewal period on an individual basis for reasons of severe illness, disability, military service or other documented hardship or good cause. Any waiver will be granted solely <ins>at</ins> the discretion of the Board. </p>
<p class="indent">2. The Board may extend the time within which to fulfill continuing education requirements to a licensee during a given continuing education renewal period on an individual basis for reasons of hardship, such as severe illness, disability, military service or other good cause. Any waiver or extension of time will be granted solely in the discretion of the Board. </p>
<p class="indent">3. A licensee must submit a written request for a waiver of continuing education requirements (L1.), or extension of time to fulfill continuing education requirements (L2.) to complete continuing education requirements. The request must be made in writing, under penalty of perjury, and must set forth with specificity the reasons for requesting the waiver or extension and, in the case of the waiver request, the portion of the renewal period during which the licensee was not engaged in the practice of marriage and family therapy. The licensee shall submit to the Board all documentation in support of the request for waiver or extension and such additional information or documentation as the Board may request in support of the waiver or extension. </p>
<p class="indent">4. Waivers of the minimum continuing education requirements may be granted for up to one-half (1/2) of the twenty-four (24) hours of continuing education required for any two-year (biennial) renewal period. Extensions of time (6 month extensions) may be granted by the Board for a period not to exceed one (1) calendar year. The grant of an extension by the Board will result in the renewal of a license based on the condition that the licensee completes the continuing education requirement by the deadline established by the Board. </p>
<p class="indent">5. A waiver of continuing education requirements granted pursuant to this section shall be effective only for the biennial period in which such waiver is granted. If the condition(s) which necessitated the waiver continues into the next biennial period, a licensee who seeks another waiver must apply to the Board for a renewal of such waiver for the new biennial period. </p>
<p class="indent">6. If an extension of time is granted, the license will be placed on active status, but the license shall be automatically changed to inactive status at the end of the extension period unless the licensee satisfies the continuing education requirement prior to that time. When the license is placed on inactive status, the licensee shall cease all activity requiring a license. </p>
<p class="indent">7. A licensee shall apply for a waiver or extension of continuing education requirements no later than thirty (30) calendar days prior to the end of the biennial licensing period for which the waiver or extension is requested. All requests shall be sent to the office of the Board, by certified mail, return receipt requested. </p>
<p class="indent">8. An extension of time shall not be granted to any licensee who obtained an extension in the immediately preceding renewal or reporting period in which the licensee held an active license, except in the case of a licensee who is unable to complete the requirements due to military service commitment pursuant to a combat or national emergency assignment. </p>
<p class="indent">9. The Board may, as a condition of any extension or waiver granted, require the licensee to make up a portion of the continuing education requirement in the manner determined by the Board. </p>
<p class="indent">Source: Miss. Code Ann. &#xa7;&#xa7;73-53-11(1) (c), (k), (m), (n) and (s), 73-54-11(1) and 73-54-27(4) (Supp. 2011). </p>
<p class="indent">Rule 4.2 Renewal of License </p>
<p class="indent">A. <u>Expiration Date</u>: All licenses expire on September 30 of the second year of <u> </u>the initial license and all future two (2) year renewal terms. All licenses not renewed on or before September 30 of the appropriate year will lapse. The Board will not assume responsibility for late renewal applications delayed or lost in the mail. </p>
<p class="indent">B. <u>Renewal Term of Two Years</u>: All renewals will be for a full two (2) year <u> </u>term beginning October 1 and ending September 30. </p>
<p class="indent">C. <u>Notice of Renewal</u>: The Board will send a reminder of renewal and a <u> </u>renewal application to all licensees at the latest address of record on file with the Board. Failure to receive a renewal notice from the Board will not relieve the license holder from the renewal requirement. It is the responsibility of the licensee to maintain an accurate address in their file by sending promptly to the Board a signed notice of any change of address. </p>
<p class="indent">D. Online renewal became available on August 1, 2008. Licensees are encouraged to renew using the online format. Renewal windows will be available from August 1 to September 30 each renewal cycle. Online renewal is available only to active licensees in good standing. </p>
<p class="indent">E. Completed Application for Renewal: The Board cannot act on an application for renewal until it is complete with all the supporting documents, continuing education summary and the renewal fee. If the licensee has never had to submit to a Criminal History Record Information Check, renewing licensees must submit to a current fingerprint criminal history record information check (or FBI name check) conducted by the appropriate governmental authority or authorities within one-hundred eighty (180) calendar days of the completed application. This criminal history record information check must be received by the Board directly from the appropriate governmental authority or authorities, not from the applicant. </p>
<p class="indent">F. <u>Renewal Fee</u>: the renewal fee covers the two (2) year term, and must be paid <u> </u>in full with the renewal application and supporting documentation and no later than the expiration date of the license. </p>
<p class="indent">G. <u>Responsibility of Licensee for Renewal</u>: It is the responsibility of the <u> </u>licensee to obtain renewal application materials from the Board, to obtain the required approved continuing education with verification, and to see that their license is renewed on time. These materials are available online at the Board's website. Failure to receive a notice of renewal does not absolve the licensee of their responsibility to renew the license before the expiration date. Practicing under an expired or a lapsed license is prohibited. It is, likewise, a misdemeanor punishable by law. </p>
<p class="indent">H. <u>Inactive Renewals</u>: Anyone returning from inactive status must meet the <u> </u>continuing education requirements for the immediate two (2) years prior to the application for renewal or reactivation of license. </p>
<p class="indent">Source: Miss. Code Ann. &#xa7;&#xa7;73-53-11(1) (c) and (e), 73-53-15, 73-54-11(1) and 73-54-27 . </p>
<p class="indent">Rule 4.3 Reinstatement of License </p>
<p class="indent">A. <b><u>General Requirements for Reinstatement</u></b><b> </b> </p>
<p class="indent">1. All conditions related to the suspension, revocation, disciplinary action, or order or directive of the Board must have been completed or met to the Board's satisfaction. </p>
<p class="indent">2. None of the prohibited acts exist as are described in Sections 73-53- 17 and 73-53-29 of the Mississippi Code of 1972, as amended, and/or Part 1901, Chapter 4, Rule 3 3.1. </p>
<p class="indent">3. The former licensee verifies, by submitting to the Board a notarized affidavit, that they have not engaged in the practice of marriage and family therapy in this state or any other state, or used a title denoting marriage and family therapist qualifications since the expiration, suspension or revocation of his or her license, unless he or she qualifies for exemption from licensure as a marriage and family therapist as provided by Section 73-54-9 of the Mississippi Code of 1972 as amended, or they hold a valid license issued by another state and his or her practice was confined to the state which issued the license. </p>
<p class="indent">4. The licensee must apply for a new license and must meet the requirements and conditions for licensure set forth in the governing law and the rules and regulations that are in effect at the time the new application or re-application is received by the Board. </p>
<p class="indent">5. The former licensee must submit to the Board a completed application for reinstatement on forms prescribed by the Board and all supporting documentation. </p>
<p class="indent">6. The former licensee must include a letter with the application for reinstatement explaining the reasons for applying for reinstatement. </p>
<p class="indent">7. The former licensee must provide satisfactory documentation of completion of all approved continuing education requirements specified by Board Rules and Regulations that would have been required to maintain a current license for the entire period the license has been lapsed or inactive; </p>
<p class="indent">8. The former licensee must pay the reinstatement costs and any other costs or fees required by the Board. </p>
<p class="indent">Source: Miss. Code Ann. &#xa7;&#xa7;73-53-11(1)(c), (d), (e), (g), (k) and (n), 73-53-23(4), 73-54-11, and 73-54-27(3) (Supp. 2011). </p>
<p class="indent"><b>Part1903 Chapter 5 FEES AND ADMINISTRATIVE COSTS </b> </p>
<p class="indent">Rule 5.1 Philosophy </p>
<p class="indent">The Board receives no financial appropriation from the State to underwrite the costs of providing the licensure services. The Board is very sensitive to controlling costs, but fees and administrative costs are necessary for licensure to exist. </p>
<p class="indent">Source: Miss. Code Ann. &#xa7;&#xa7;73-53-10(1), 73-53-11(1)(c) and 73-54-11(1) (Supp. 2011). </p>
<p class="indent">Rule 5.2 The Fee Schedule </p>
<p class="indent">A. Application to Take AMFTRB Examination in Marital and Family Therapy fee....................$ 25.00</p>
<p class="indent">B. Application fee for licensure as a Marriage and Family Therapist, nonrefundable ....................... $ 100.00</p>
<p class="indent">C. LMFTA Application fee............... $ 25.00</p>
<p class="indent">D. Initial LMFT license fee...............$ 200.00</p>
<p class="indent">(May be prorated for first year, see below)</p>
<p class="indent">E. Initial LMFTA license fee ...............$ 75.00</p>
<p class="indent"> (May be prorated for first year, see below)</p>
<p class="indent">F. Renewal fee for LMFT (2 years) ....................... $ 200.00</p>
<p class="indent">G. Renewal fee for LMFTA license (2 years)........$100.00</p>
<p class="indent">H. The Board may charge administrative/processing costs as follows:</p>
<p class="indent">1. Duplicate license ................................. $ 25.00</p>
<p class="indent">2. Replace lost license .......................... $ 25.00</p>
<p class="indent">3. Reinstatement (plus renewal cost) .............. $ 35.00</p>
<p class="indent">4. Electronic copy of LMFT licensee address list ..... $50.00</p>
<p class="indent">5. Copying fee ($1.00 per page plus cost of retrieving information)</p>
<p class="indent">6. Postgraduate Supervision Plan Approval Fee... $100.00</p>
<p class="indent">7. Application for Continuing Education Provider Status.$125.00</p>
<p class="indent">8. Application for Individual Continuing Education Offering... $50.00</p>
<p class="indent">9. Application Packet ........... $ 10.00</p>
<p class="indent">(initial applicants will be issued one copy free of charge upon request; it is also available online at no cost)</p>
<p class="indent">10. Copy of rules and regulations......... $ 20.00</p>
<p class="indent"> (initial applicants will be issued one copy free of charge upon request; it is also available online at no cost)</p>
<p class="indent">11. Name Change fee................$10.00</p>
<p class="indent">12. License verification for another state.......$25.00</p>
<p class="indent">13. Late renewal fee...............$50.00</p>
<p class="indent">Source: Miss. Code Ann. &#xa7;&#xa7;73-53-11(1) (c), (g) and (o), 73-53-15, 73-54-11(1) and 73-54-27 (Supp. 2011). </p>
<p class="indent">Rule 5.3 General Rules Regarding Fees and Administrative Costs </p>
<p class="indent">A. Fees and administrative costs are payable by cashier's check, money order, or credit cards accepted by the Board. Checks and money orders should be made payable to the Board of Examiners for SW/MFT. All fees and costs are <b><i>non-refundable</i></b><i>.</i> </p>
<p class="indent">B. The Board will not issue or renew a license until all outstanding fees and administrative costs have been paid. </p>
<p class="indent">C. The application fee must accompany the completed application, and is non-refundable. </p>
<p class="indent">D. When the Board notifies an applicant that their license application has been approved, the initial license fee (prorated for the first year, if applicable) must be paid in full before the license can be issued. </p>
<p class="indent">E. The renewal fee must be paid on or before September 30 of the second year the license is in effect (the expiration date). The full renewal fee for two years must accompany the renewal application. </p>
<p class="indent">Source: Miss. Code Ann. &#xa7;&#xa7;73-53-11(1) (c), (g) and (o), 73-53-15, 73-54-11(1) and 73-54-27 (Supp. 2011). </p>
<p class="indent">Rule 5.4 Proration of the First Year Portion of Initial License Fee </p>
<p class="indent">Since all licenses have an expiration date of September 30, the initial license period may be less than two (2) full years, depending on the date the application was approved by the Board. The first year's portion of the initial two (2) year fee may be prorated and billed in the following manner: </p>
<p class="indent">A. License applications approved between October 1 and March 31 will require the full initial license fee for the first two years. </p>
<p class="indent">B. For license applications approved between April 1 and September 30, the first years portion of the initial two (2) years will be reduced by one half. </p>
<p class="indent"><b><u>Responsibility of the Applicant or Licensee:</u></b> <b><u> </u></b> </p>
<p class="indent">It is the responsibility of the applicant or licensee to see that their license fees and renewal fees are paid in a timely manner. Failure to receive a notice of renewal or payment due from the board does not relieve the person of their responsibility to pay the fees before the deadline. The Board assumes no responsibility for fees that are lost in the mail, arrive late or otherwise do not reach the Board on time. </p>
<p class="indent"><b>Adjustment of Fee Scale: </b> </p>
<p class="indent">The Board may increase the fees at the discretion of the Board, within the limits provided by State Statute. </p>
<p class="indent">Source: Miss. Code Ann. &#xa7;&#xa7;73-53-11(1) (c), (g) and (o), 73-53-15, 73-54-11(1) and 73-54-27 (Supp. 2011). </p>
<p class="indent">Amended: January 1, 2022 Effective: </p>
</text>
</document>
</regtext>